<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Diary on CipherBlog</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/</link><description>Recent content in The Diary on CipherBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 02:51:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dumbcooks.com/diary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/29-12-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 01:04:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/29-12-2022/</guid><description>Year 2022 is almost over. I guess only 3 days left, I don&amp;rsquo;t count. I should say, this is one of the most enjoyed years in my life. Met a handful of funny lovely new friends.
I started to write my own OS. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;ll ever be usefull. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this only for educational purpose. Now I know how to place a useful instruction on 0x07C0 memory address of the RAM and load the OS to the RAM.</description></item><item><title>16 09 2022</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/16-09-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:54:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/16-09-2022/</guid><description>Why the fish move?
Fish in my fish tank move. I know, that&amp;rsquo;s the expected behavior, but why?
Apart from eating, they have no other thing to do. So why do they move. What&amp;rsquo;s going on in their heads? Are they thinking, &amp;ldquo;Oh I&amp;rsquo;ve to go there. Great, now I&amp;rsquo;m here, I&amp;rsquo;ve to go back to the previous place and come back here?&amp;rdquo;
We, humans too move. Why? At the core, we too only have those 2 things the fish do in their lives, eating and reproduction.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/19-08-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 14:03:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/19-08-2022/</guid><description>She sells sea shells on the sea shore. Went to the sea shore today.
Sea, as seen by someone from the shore should be the most beautiful thing on Earth. Someone who&amp;rsquo;s drowning may see it as the most dangerous place to be. A sailer sailing for months may see it as a prison. Kids playing on the shore, oh for them, it&amp;rsquo;s heaven.
Just different perspectives.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/12-08-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 14:03:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/12-08-2022/</guid><description>Had to repair my bicycle. Then clean up my desktop PC. I removed the processor to clean. That little circuit I hold for about 5 minutes worth more than my mother&amp;rsquo;s jwelery.
Fan above it had accumelated so much dust. Cleaned them. Processor had dust too. Blowed most of the dust but could not clean well because I don&amp;rsquo;t have proper equipment. Cleaned the RAM pins and VGA pins.
Cool, now PC works.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/04-08-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 15:21:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/04-08-2022/</guid><description>This is the first diary entry. Is having a diary in a personal website good? Idk, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth a try.
Today&amp;rsquo;s cycling journey is cool. I covered almost 15km.</description></item></channel></rss>