<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CipherBlog</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/</link><description>Recent content on CipherBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 19:30:44 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dumbcooks.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>16 09 2022</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/16-09-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:54:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/16-09-2022/</guid><description>Why the fish move?
Fish in my fish tank move. I know, that&amp;rsquo;s the expected behavior, but why?
Apart from eating, they have no other thing to do. So why do they move. What&amp;rsquo;s going on in their heads? Are they thinking, &amp;ldquo;Oh I&amp;rsquo;ve to go there. Great, now I&amp;rsquo;m here, I&amp;rsquo;ve to go back to the previous place and come back here?&amp;rdquo;
We, humans too move. Why? At the core, we too only have those 2 things the fish do in their lives, eating and reproduction.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 03:13:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m Adeepa Gunathilake and here&amp;rsquo;s my &amp;ldquo;about&amp;rdquo; page. I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone would even read this, but writing anyway. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to social engineer me, this section might help you. So take notes :)
I am just a curious student. I love making computers go beep boop. I was born in mid August some year near 2000 and ever since then, I try to figure out how this world works.</description></item><item><title>Contact Details</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 18:15:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/contact/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s my contact details:
email: adeepagunathilake@gmail.com mastodon: @cipherdragon@mstdn.starnix.network github: github.com/cipherdragon My gpg key is available on the MIT keyserver. Download from here or use the following command to import.
1 gpg --recv-keys EFB5800FD17CE9498DCDB508F933FCFED4834ADE That&amp;rsquo;s it. That&amp;rsquo;s how you contact me if you ever wants to.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/19-08-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 14:03:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/19-08-2022/</guid><description>She sells sea shells on the sea shore. Went to the sea shore today.
Sea, as seen by someone from the shore should be the most beautiful thing on Earth. Someone who&amp;rsquo;s drowning may see it as the most dangerous place to be. A sailer sailing for months may see it as a prison. Kids playing on the shore, oh for them, it&amp;rsquo;s heaven.
Just different perspectives.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/12-08-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 14:03:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/12-08-2022/</guid><description>Had to repair my bicycle. Then clean up my desktop PC. I removed the processor to clean. That little circuit I hold for about 5 minutes worth more than my mother&amp;rsquo;s jwelery.
Fan above it had accumelated so much dust. Cleaned them. Processor had dust too. Blowed most of the dust but could not clean well because I don&amp;rsquo;t have proper equipment. Cleaned the RAM pins and VGA pins.
Cool, now PC works.</description></item><item><title>Generate QR codes quickly in linux terminal</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/generate-qr-linux-terminal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 20:07:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/generate-qr-linux-terminal/</guid><description>Recently I had to type a long password to an app, but it&amp;rsquo;s super complex that typing is a headache. Password was in my password manager on laptop I decided to transfer the password using QR codes and then copy it.
Generating a QR is nothing hard these days, tons of online services for this now, but the thing is, my data is sensitive. Online services are not an option.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/04-08-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 15:21:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/04-08-2022/</guid><description>This is the first diary entry. Is having a diary in a personal website good? Idk, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth a try.
Today&amp;rsquo;s cycling journey is cool. I covered almost 15km.</description></item><item><title>Lion and the Friend.</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/lion-and-the-friend/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 23:07:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/lion-and-the-friend/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a story. Happened in Africa.
There were 2 friends. One day they went to the jungle. All of a sudden, they saw a lion. It may be hungry, don&amp;rsquo;t know for sure because, you know, it never told me. The problem is, this animal was approching them.
One friend got down to tie the lace of his shoe. The other asked, &amp;ldquo;what are you doing? You can&amp;rsquo;t outrun a lion&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>I don't trust computers. Am I a caveman?</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/do-not-trust-computers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 02:51:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/do-not-trust-computers/</guid><description>My high school history teacher worked at a local bank once and he said some customers don&amp;rsquo;t trust computers. They don&amp;rsquo;t trust money counting machines. They don&amp;rsquo;t trust ATMs. They are afraid of getting less money out of them than it records. These people are mostly seniors. Internet and computers wasn&amp;rsquo;t a big thing in their ages.
Why a bank employee gave up his job for teaching kids? I don&amp;rsquo;t know but he&amp;rsquo;s not dumb either.</description></item></channel></rss>