<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CipherBlog</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/</link><description>Recent content on CipherBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 19:30:44 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dumbcooks.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2023-08-18/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 15:21:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2023-08-18/</guid><description>Today marks the day that marks the end of the IEEE 2022/2023 event&amp;rsquo;s, with the final preparations for our signature event IX 23, we are planning to end our term with a blast, with a great set of exco to take on the challenges of IEEE, we look forward for what great feats they are planning to conduct.
A note by Tharana</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 16:19:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/about/</guid><description>Hello world!
I&amp;rsquo;m Adeepa Gunathilake. Currently a BSc. Artificial Intelligence and Data Science undergraduate. Since I use no social media, this website is the only major place I participate in the internet other than on github and stackoverflow.
Things I love to do Cycling Programming Sleeping Spending time with my close friends Enjoying nature Youtube channels I enjoy watching I love the content following youtubers make so much that I decided to give them a shout out here.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2023-02-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 15:21:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2023-02-14/</guid><description>The greatest glory in living lies not in never falling, but in rising every time we fall.
- A quote by Nelson Mandela -
Note left by Sewmina Fernando</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2023-02-12/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 18:02:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2023-02-12/</guid><description>Worked so hard to build a very eye catching javascript animation only to remove it later because brave browser on mobile does not work well with it.</description></item><item><title>The Library</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/library/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:04:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/library/</guid><description>This is the library. This is where I place my favorite articles, books etc.
E-books and articles Unabomber Manifesto (pdf) Web articles The Website Obesity Crisis Is software getting worse? How does it feel to be a lab rat</description></item><item><title>Git Cheatsheet</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/git-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 20:36:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/git-cheatsheet/</guid><description>Git is a version control system, another great invention of Linus Torvalds. This will be a basic cheatsheet containing common git commands targeted at beginners. See the links in the bottom for advanced git cheatsheets.
Common git workflow To create (initialize) a git repository
1 $&amp;gt; git init To clone a remote git repository
1 $&amp;gt; git clone [remote repo url] To see the current status of the working directory</description></item><item><title>What are Web Cookies?</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/web-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 18:53:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/web-cookies/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick read.
Cookies are small text files websites set on your browser when you visit them. These files hold pieces of labeled data such as username and password.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of a cookie file.
1 2 3 username=&amp;#34;some random username&amp;#34; password=&amp;#34;super complex password&amp;#34; last_login=1675604361 When you close the website and revisit the site again, that site can read the cookie file it stored earlier and apply settings you set earlier.</description></item><item><title>Markdown and Future Proofing Documents</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/markdown-and-future-proofing-documents/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 11:50:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/markdown-and-future-proofing-documents/</guid><description>Markdown is the simplest text markup language other than gemini. I would not be incorrect if I say markdown will only be second to gemtext and plain .txt text files in terms of simplicity. Unfortunately, there are more people who don&amp;rsquo;t even know what markdown is than the people who know.
Jump directly to markdown cheatsheet
If you want to take some notes during a lecture or during a presentation etc, your note will mostly be plain text.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2022-12-29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 01:04:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2022-12-29/</guid><description>Year 2022 is almost over. I guess only 3 days left, I don&amp;rsquo;t count. I should say, this is one of the most enjoyed years in my life. Met a handful of funny lovely new friends.
I started to write my own OS. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;ll ever be usefull. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this only for educational purpose. Now I know how to place a useful instruction on 0x07C0 memory address of the RAM and load the OS to the RAM.</description></item><item><title>All About CLI</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/all-about-cli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 01:28:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/all-about-cli/</guid><description>This article will be on &amp;ldquo;Command Line Interface,&amp;rdquo; (CLI in short) aka the black box hackers type into using blue or green text in movies. Terminal, console and command prompt are other common words too.
If you think there&amp;rsquo;s no reason for you to learn about CLI in 2022 because now you have glowing user interfaces, trust me, you&amp;rsquo;re wrong, you&amp;rsquo;ll only be a soydev, a sarcasm generator for the programming community.</description></item><item><title>How to Ask a Question</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/how-to-ask-a-question/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 17:39:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/how-to-ask-a-question/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s September again!
Today&amp;rsquo;s the 10,640th September. People usually ask me questions related to IT, specially related to programming. Many questions are just garbage. People don&amp;rsquo;t know to ask questions the right way.
I see many of these &amp;ldquo;garbage&amp;rdquo; questions on stackoverflow. When I see them, I just leave a advice in the comments and move on, but if the question is utter garbage, I immediatly downvote. This is the same procedure many other stackoverflow users follow.</description></item><item><title>16 09 2022</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2022-09-16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:54:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2022-09-16/</guid><description>Why the fish move?
Fish in my fish tank move. I know, that&amp;rsquo;s the expected behavior, but why?
Apart from eating, they have no other thing to do. So why do they move. What&amp;rsquo;s going on in their heads? Are they thinking, &amp;ldquo;Oh I&amp;rsquo;ve to go there. Great, now I&amp;rsquo;m here, I&amp;rsquo;ve to go back to the previous place and come back here?&amp;rdquo;
We, humans too move. Why? At the core, we too only have those 2 things the fish do in their lives, eating and reproduction.</description></item><item><title>Contact Details</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 18:15:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/contact/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s my contact details:
email: adeepagunathilake@gmail.com mastodon: @cipherdragon@mstdn.starnix.network github: github.com/cipherdragon Update (2023-02-09):
I lost access to my gpg private keys, so I won&amp;rsquo;t sign any documents with the keys I&amp;rsquo;ve published on public keyservers. I might generate a new key pair and put the public key here, but for now, I have no gpg keys.
That&amp;rsquo;s it. That&amp;rsquo;s how you contact me if you ever wants to.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2022-08-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 14:03:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2022-08-19/</guid><description>She sells sea shells on the sea shore. Went to the sea shore today.
Sea, as seen by someone from the shore should be the most beautiful thing on Earth. Someone who&amp;rsquo;s drowning may see it as the most dangerous place to be. A sailer sailing for months may see it as a prison. Kids playing on the shore, oh for them, it&amp;rsquo;s heaven.
Just different perspectives.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2022-08-12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 14:03:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2022-08-12/</guid><description>Had to repair my bicycle. Then clean up my desktop PC. I removed the processor to clean. That little circuit I hold for about 5 minutes worth more than my mother&amp;rsquo;s jwelery.
Fan above it had accumelated so much dust. Cleaned them. Processor had dust too. Blowed most of the dust but could not clean well because I don&amp;rsquo;t have proper equipment. Cleaned the RAM pins and VGA pins.
Cool, now PC works.</description></item><item><title>Generate QR codes quickly in linux terminal</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/generate-qr-linux-terminal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 20:07:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/generate-qr-linux-terminal/</guid><description>Recently I had to type a long password to an app, but it&amp;rsquo;s super complex that typing is a headache. Password was in my password manager on laptop I decided to transfer the password using QR codes and then copy it.
Generating a QR is nothing hard these days, tons of online services for this now, but the thing is, my data is sensitive. Online services are not an option.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2022-08-04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 15:21:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/diary/2022-08-04/</guid><description>This is the first diary entry. Is having a diary in a personal website good? Idk, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth a try.
Today&amp;rsquo;s cycling journey is cool. I covered almost 15km.</description></item><item><title>Lion and the Friend.</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/lion-and-the-friend/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 23:07:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/lion-and-the-friend/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a story. Happened in Africa.
There were 2 friends. One day they went to the jungle. All of a sudden, they saw a lion. It may be hungry, don&amp;rsquo;t know for sure because, you know, it never told me. The problem is, this animal was approching them.
One friend got down to tie the lace of his shoe. The other asked, &amp;ldquo;what are you doing? You can&amp;rsquo;t outrun a lion&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>