<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on CipherBlog</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on CipherBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 09:32:40 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dumbcooks.com/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Linked List Java</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/linked-list-java/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 09:32:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/linked-list-java/</guid><description>Java linked list implementation for my friends&amp;rsquo; reference.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 public class LinkedList { int size; Node head; Node tail; public void insert(int value) { if (head == null) { head = new Node(null, null, value); tail = head; return; } tail.</description></item><item><title>Git Cheatsheet</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/git-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 20:36:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/git-cheatsheet/</guid><description>Git is a version control system, another great invention of Linus Torvalds. This will be a basic cheatsheet containing common git commands targeted at beginners. See the links in the bottom for advanced git cheatsheets.
Common git workflow To create (initialize) a git repository
1 $&amp;gt; git init To clone a remote git repository
1 $&amp;gt; git clone [remote repo url] To see the current status of the working directory</description></item><item><title>All About CLI</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/all-about-cli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 01:28:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/all-about-cli/</guid><description>This article will be on &amp;ldquo;Command Line Interface,&amp;rdquo; (CLI in short) aka the black box hackers type into using blue or green text in movies. Terminal, console and command prompt are other common words too.
If you think there&amp;rsquo;s no reason for you to learn about CLI in 2022 because now you have glowing user interfaces, trust me, you&amp;rsquo;re wrong, you&amp;rsquo;ll only be a soydev, a sarcasm generator for the programming community.</description></item><item><title>How to Ask a Question</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/how-to-ask-a-question/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 17:39:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/how-to-ask-a-question/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s September again!
Today&amp;rsquo;s the 10,640th September. People usually ask me questions related to IT, specially related to programming. Many questions are just garbage. People don&amp;rsquo;t know to ask questions the right way.
I see many of these &amp;ldquo;garbage&amp;rdquo; questions on stackoverflow. When I see them, I just leave a advice in the comments and move on, but if the question is utter garbage, I immediatly downvote. This is the same procedure many other stackoverflow users follow.</description></item><item><title>Generate QR codes quickly in linux terminal</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/generate-qr-linux-terminal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 20:07:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/generate-qr-linux-terminal/</guid><description>Recently I had to type a long password to an app, but it&amp;rsquo;s super complex that typing is a headache. Password was in my password manager on laptop I decided to transfer the password using QR codes and then copy it.
Generating a QR is nothing hard these days, tons of online services for this now, but the thing is, my data is sensitive. Online services are not an option.</description></item></channel></rss>