<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web log on CipherBlog</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Web log on CipherBlog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 02:51:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dumbcooks.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Markdown and Future Proofing Documents</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/markdown-and-future-proofing-documents/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 11:50:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/markdown-and-future-proofing-documents/</guid><description>Markdown is the simplest text markup language other than gemini. I would not be incorrect if I say markdown will only be second to gemtext and plain .txt text files in terms of simplicity. Unfortunately, there are more people who don&amp;rsquo;t even know what markdown is than the people who know.
Jump directly to markdown cheatsheet
If you want to take some notes during a lecture or during a presentation etc, your note will mostly be plain text.</description></item><item><title>All About CLI</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/all-about-cli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 01:28:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/all-about-cli/</guid><description>This article will be on &amp;ldquo;Command Line Interface,&amp;rdquo; (CLI in short) aka the black box hackers type into using blue or green text in movies. Terminal, console and command prompt are other common words too.
If you think there&amp;rsquo;s no reason for you to learn about CLI in 2022 because now you have glowing user interfaces, trust me, you&amp;rsquo;re wrong, you&amp;rsquo;ll only be a soydev, a sarcasm generator for the programming community.</description></item><item><title>How to Ask a Question</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/how-to-ask-a-question/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 17:39:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/how-to-ask-a-question/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s September again!
Today&amp;rsquo;s the 10,640th September. People usually ask me questions related to IT, specially related to programming. Many questions are just garbage. People don&amp;rsquo;t know to ask questions the right way.
I see many of these &amp;ldquo;garbage&amp;rdquo; questions on stackoverflow. When I see them, I just leave a advice in the comments and move on, but if the question is utter garbage, I immediatly downvote. This is the same procedure many other stackoverflow users follow.</description></item><item><title>Generate QR codes quickly in linux terminal</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/generate-qr-linux-terminal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 20:07:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/generate-qr-linux-terminal/</guid><description>Recently I had to type a long password to an app, but it&amp;rsquo;s super complex that typing is a headache. Password was in my password manager on laptop I decided to transfer the password using QR codes and then copy it.
Generating a QR is nothing hard these days, tons of online services for this now, but the thing is, my data is sensitive. Online services are not an option.</description></item><item><title>Lion and the Friend.</title><link>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/lion-and-the-friend/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 23:07:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dumbcooks.com/blog/lion-and-the-friend/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a story. Happened in Africa.
There were 2 friends. One day they went to the jungle. All of a sudden, they saw a lion. It may be hungry, don&amp;rsquo;t know for sure because, you know, it never told me. The problem is, this animal was approching them.
One friend got down to tie the lace of his shoe. The other asked, &amp;ldquo;what are you doing? You can&amp;rsquo;t outrun a lion&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>